Charlie Grogan

Teaching Assistant/Tutor - Full Stack Web Development

Contact Info

Phone

847.920.4929

E-Mail

grogan.charlie@gmail.com

Website

www.charlesgrogan.com

GitHub

github.com/CharlesGrogan

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/Charles-Grogan

Technical Skills

React/Redux

Node.js

Express.js

JavaScript - ES6

iQuery

MySQL

MongoDB

Ruby on Rails

RESTful API

HTML-5

CSS-3

Front-End Frameworks

Git

Heroku

NPM/Yarn

Mocha/Chai/Jest/Enzyme

Soft Skills

Servant Leadership Style Written/Oral Communication

Emotional Intelligence

Futuristic

Creative

Competitive

Intellectual Strategic

irategi

Agile

Education

Northwestern University
Full-Stack Web Development
Coding Boot Camp
Graduated October 2018

Ohio University
Bachelor of Science
Human and Consumer Sciences

Professional Summary

Experienced professional with 8+ years of management experience specializing in team management and strategic planning. Seeking to leverage servant leadership abilities and expertise to have a successful career in software development. Talents and skills include critical inquiry and problem solving, and adaptability in agile environments that will prove essential as a successful software developer.

Related Projects

Virtual Hostel - Full Stack Application Project Manager, Lead Developer

Virtual Hostel is designed for travelers to share their experiences with words and photos to a community of global travelers.

Technologies: React.js, Mongo database, Mongoose, RESTful API, JavaScript, jQuery, Bulma CSS framework, Passport login-in, Ajax, Axios, Git, HTML, & Heroku

Campaign Query – Full Stack Application Project Manager, Lead Developer

Campaign Query uses data visualizations to showcase campaign finance contributions from the 2016 election cycle

Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, JavaScript, jQuery, amCharts, High Charts, MySQL, Sequelize, APIs, Ajax, CSS, HTML, Git, & Heroku

bAmazon – Node.js Application

Sole Developer

bAmazon is a simulated store front application that tracks inventory and calculates price based on the quantity purchased.

Technologies: Node.js, NPM Inquirer, MySQL, NPM MySQL, Cli-Tables2

Experience

Teaching Assistant/Tutor – Web Development December 2018 – Current

Trilogy Education Chicago, Illinois

- Student code review, analysis, and optimization
- Collaborate with instructional staff to ensure the overall success of each student
- Teach students best practices and methodologies how to find to problem solve, search for resources, and better understand documentation
- Coach students through complex problems using mechanisms to help them describe and fully understand the task/code at hand

Sales Consultant October 2015 – June 2018

Enterprise Holdings Chicago, Illinois

- Consistently produced on average at 120% of my yearly sales goal
- Strong analytical skills create new strategies focusing on client retention, referral metrics, sales pipelines using Salesforce
- Thrive on developing creative and strategic solutions
- Lead product presentations and post-sale follow-ups

Branch Manager February 2013 – October 2015

Enterprise Holdings Chicago, Illinois

- Managed book of business consisting of nearly 70 national and local accounts, developed strategies to create growth, retention, and 100% business saturation
- Increased branch profit by 80% in same period (\$95,000 to \$171,000 in total profit dollars) which was 60% above my goal credit to building strong relationships and strategic planning
- Supervisor of multiple locations, including O'Hare International Airport where I supervised for nearly 125 full time and part time employee